Donald Baxter MacMillan Collection M118
George J. Mitchell Department of Special Collections & Archives, Bowdoin College Library, Brunswick, Maine 04011
- Diaries and Journals - Originals, 1902-1957, M118.5; 7.5 linear feet
  - 1947 Log Book: BOWDOIN-MacMillan Arctic Expedition of 1947 to Greenland, June 21-23, 1947 (no. 50) (Volume 50)
  - 1948 Diary: MacMillan Arctic Expedition 1948, June 3-Sept. 15, 1948 (no. 51) (Volume 51)
  - 1949, 1950 Diary: MacMillan Arctic Expedition, May 1-Sept. 18, 1949; June 12-Sept. 11, 1950 (no. 52) (Volume 52)
  - 1953-1954 Diary: MacMillan Arctic Expedition, Oct. 30, 1953-Sept. 29, 1954 (no. 53) (Volume 53)
  - 1957 Field Diary: air flight over North Pole, Aug. 31-Sept. 15, 1957 (no. 54) (Volume 54)
  - "Birds and Animals" (in Crocker Land Expedition bound notebook) [n.d.] (no. 55) (Volume 55)
  - "Ethnological Notes", Eskimos of Smith Sound Tribe (in Crocker Land Expedition bound notebook) [1914-16] (no. 56) (Volume 56)
  - "Measurements of Esquimaux" [n.d.] (no. 57) (Volume 57)
  - Field notebook listing Eskimos aboard the ROOSEVELT; names of Smith Sound Eskimos; "Information about Dr. Cook" (concerning Cook's trip to Pole and statements of the Eskimos who accom-panied him) [1908-09] (no. 58) (Volume 58)
  - Dictionary of Eskimo words and phrases [n.d.] (no. 59) (Volume 59)
  - Eskimo dictionary collected in N. Greenland [1913-17] (no. 60) (Volume 60)
  - Eskimo vocabulary, English-Eskimo, A-Z [1913-17] (no. 61) (Volume-folio 61)
  - Eskimo grammar (not by DBM) [1913-17] (no. 62) (Volume 62)
  - Eskimo language,"Hudson Bay", English to Eskimo [1913-17] (no. 63) (Volume 63)
  - English/Eskimo dictionary compiled by F.W. Peacock [1913-17] (no. 64) (Volume 64)
  - "Facts for Book", misc. information re. Arctic [1913-17] (no. 67) (Volume 65)
  - Important dates in exploration, includes a partial list of MacMillan's expeditions (no. 68) (Volume 66)
  - "Notes, Arctic Expeditions"-notes on various expeditions of Otto Sverdrup (no. 69) (Volume 67)
  - Notebook in DBM's hand listing titles of books on the Arctic (no. 70) (Volume 68)
  - Bibliography of Arctic Books in the MacMillan Library (no. 70a) (Volume 69)
  - Catalogue of books in the MacMillan Library (no. 70b) (Volume 70)
  - Lectures-listed alphabetically by town and/or club (no. 71) (Volume-folio 71)
  - "The Traditional Labrador Eskimos" by Ernest S. Burch, Jr., Princeton Univ., Dept. of Economics and Sociology, for A.B. degree, Apr. 22, 1960 (no. 72) (Volume 72)
  - "A short history of the Arctic whale fisheries" by Stanton A. Cook, term paper for Harvard Univ., Jan. 8, 1950 (no. 73) (Volume 73)
  - "Journal of a voyage from Okkak, on the coast of Labrador to Ungava Bay...in 1811" by Benjamin Kolhmeister and George Knoch...London, for the Brethren's Society for the furtherance of the Gospel among the heathen, 1814. Ts which DBM had copied from the volume found in the Rare Book Section of the Library of Congress (no. 74) (Volume-folio 74)
  - "Tragedy on the Delta" by John P. Jackson [account of the loss and death of George W. Delong in his 1879 attempt to reach the N. Pole] (no. 75) (Volume 75)
  - Sketches and illustrations for "Tragedy on the Delta" (no. 76a) (Volume 76)
  - Various maps and pencil drawings re. George W. Delong and John P. Jackson (no. 76b) (Volume-folio 77)
  - George W. Delong's North Pole Expedition 1879-81 [clippings] (no. 77) (Volume 78)
  - Ts. diary of Leo M. Davidoff from the MacMillan Arctic Expedition 1925, incl. many photos taken on expedition (no. 78) [DO NOT USE. USE COPY: M118.7 Box 6 Folder 1] [Original ms. copy of diary and literary rights are maintained by the Peary-MacMillan Arctic Musuem] (Volume-folio 79)
  - Diary of William R. Esson from the 1934 MacMillan Arctic Expedition to Labrador (Volume 80)
  - Ts. of William R. Esson's diary (Volume-folio 81)
  - Diary of Lawrence B. Flint form the 1934 Arctic Expedition (Volume 82)
  - Kenneth Sewall's ms. personal journal of the 1937 MacMillan Arctic Expedition (Volume 83)
  - Kenneth Sewall's ts. journal... (Volume 84)
  - Kenneth Sewall's journal on disk... (Volume 85)
- Diaries and Journals - Typescripts and Photocopies, 1902-1957, n.d., M118.6; 0.55 linear feet
  This series contains typescript and photocopies of various diaries and journals belonging to MacMillan regarding the Peary North Pole Expedition, the Crocker Land Expedition, or relating to arctic exploration more generally.
  Access Restrctions:
  - Diary: Swarthmore Prep. School and Worcester Academy, Feb. 3, 1902-May 4, 1902; May 2, 1904-June 9, 1904-photo-copy, partial ts (see original diary no. 1) (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - North Pole Expedition, 1908-1909 ts (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - North Pole Expedition, 1908-1909 electrostatic copy (Box 5, Folder 10-15)
  - Field Diary, No. Pole Expedition (1908-1909), Feb. 18, 1909-March 25, 1909, 2 carbon ts. (*see original journal 6) (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - North Pole Expedition, April 19-May 31, 1909; 3 copies (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Crocker Land Expedition, Feb. 12, 1914-March 26, 1915 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Crocker Land Expedition, March 28, 1915-April 11, 1916 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Crocker Land Expedition, July 25, 1913-Jan. 1, 1914 (cover) (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Crocker Land Expedition, Nov. 17, 1913-Jan. 15, 1914 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Crocker Land Expedition, July 25, 1913-Jan. 1914, ts (* see journal 15) (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Crocker Land Expedition, April 12, 1916-Feb. 14, 1917 (* see journal 18) (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - "Arctic Information" pp. 6-81 (Box 5, Folder 24-32)
  - "Arctic Information" notes and astronomical facts, pp. 50-60 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - "Arctic Information" pp. 6-81 electrostatic copy (Box 5, Folder 34-36)
  - "General Information": "Greenland Ice Fields..."; "Polar Bear"; "Adiabatic Heat"; "Air" (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - "General Information": "American Polar Expeditions"; "Arctic Fox"; "Astronomy"; "Aurora"; "Birds North of 76 deg." (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - "General Information": "Birds"; "Caribou"; "Cairns"; "Cary Islands"; "Clothing"; "Treatment of the Eskimo Dog"; "Effects of Cold..." (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - "General Information": "Colors"; "Compass Variations"; "Communication with Home"; "West Greenland Current"; "Darkness"; "Effect of Long Polar Night..."; "Deaths in the Arctic"; "Devil's Thumb" (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - "General Information": "Labrador History"; "Dogs" (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - "General Information": "Drift on the Ice"; "Efflorescence"; "Egedesminde"; "Eider Duck"; "Erik and Other Ships"; "Errors in Reporting Land"; "Expeditions from New York"; "Explorers Who Have Died..."; "Explorers Discredited"; "Polar Eskimos" (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - "General Information": "Eskimos Who Have Visited Civilization"; "Eskimo Help"; "Fire"; "Foehn Wind"; "Food"; "Facts Relating to... Loss of Franklin"; "Geology"; "Greenland"; "Halos"; "Hans Christian" (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - "General Information": "Arctic Hare"; "Russian Hermit"; "House"; "Ice Foot"; "Insanity"; "Kane Expedition..."; "Kites"; "Land Reported"; "Latent Heat"; "Lemmings"; "Littleton Island"; "Loom and Mirage"; "Strange Animals Seen" (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - "General Information": "Accumulation of Moisture"; "Musk Oxen"; "Narwhal"; "Newspapers"; "Salt Water Ice"; "Sun"; "Spirits"; "Facts Concerning the So-Called White Eskimo" (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - "General Information": "Greenland Ice Fields" through "Compass Variations" [electrostatic copy] (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - "General Information": "West Greenland Current" through "Errors in Reporting Land" [electrostatic copy] (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - "General Information": "Expeditions from New York" through "Facts Concerning the So-Called White Eskimos" [electrostatic copy] (Box 5, Folder 48)
- Notes, Clippings, Ephemera and Realia, 1884-1985, n.d., M118.7; 2.0 linear feet
  This series contains newspaper clippings, various manuscript and typescript notes and articles, and other ephemera. Within this series are clippings and articles concerning the Peary/Cook controversy, scrapbooks and photo albums; posters and press releases; certificates and awards; a run of mounted plant specimens from Labrador; and other miscellaneous ephemera and realia.
  Access Resctrictions:
  - Anthropomorphic charts on four Polar Eskimos (Crocker Land) (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Etah Sun Drawings (Crocker Land Expedition) (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Temp. records, North Greenland, Dec. 20, 1914-July 30, 1917 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Account of 1921-22 expedition to Baffin Island, ms (incomplete) (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Account of the 1925 expedition to Greenland, ms (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Account of the 1925 expedition to Greenland, ts (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Leo Davidoff Diary, 1925 expedition to Greenland, photocopy (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Account of the 1934 expedition to Labrador, Baffin Land, ms & ts (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Notes on the Eskimo of Labrador [ca. 1910], ms (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Misc. notes on the history of Maine, ms (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Ms in DBM's hand re. teaching navigation to students aboard schooner "Bowdoin" (incomplete) (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - MacMillan Arctic Association material (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - MacMillan Arctic Association material (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - List of books and papers given to the MacMillan Arctic Library, Feb. 1979, ts and photocopy (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Arctic books owned by DBM, listed alphabetically by author, ts (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Arctic books owned by DBM, listed alphabetically by title, ts (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Summary of Arctic books, April 22, 1933, ts (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Arctic books owned by DBM, listed alphabetically by title, ts (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Magazine articles by DBM, ts (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Cover containing DBM's book lists (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Notes on history of exploration of Ellesmere Land and Axel Heiberg Land, carbon ts (incomplete) (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Misc. notes on Arctic anthropology, ms & ts (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Misc. notes on the Arctic, ts (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Notes on the Arctic, ms/ts (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Cook/Peary controversy, ms/ts (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Cook/Peary controversy: News Clippings, 17 items (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Cook/Peary controversy: Printed Material (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Labrador Expedition report by J.M. Hastings, 1891 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Cover for Labrador Expedition report, 1891 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - 1925 Arctic Expedition-Log of the schooner "Bowdoin" (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Misc. notes for the 1908-1909 North Pole expedition (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Misc. clippings found at Greeley headquarters, Fort Conger; June 10th, 1909 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Scrapbook collection of autographs (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Scrapbook of newspaper clippings documenting the 1925 MacMillan Arctic Expedition, compiled by family and friends of Maynard Owen Williams (Volume-folio 1)
  - Anthropology course at Bowdoin: notes by DBM (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Anthropology course at Bowdoin: notes by DBM (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - George Borup tribute, ms (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Elisha Kent Kane material (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - "Bowdoin" Expedition crew lists (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Misc. Fragments (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Fragments (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - "Rear Admiral Donald MacMillan and Peter Pitseolak: The Arctic Connection"- talk for Bowdoin College April 3rd, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Materials regarding the schooner "Bowdoin" (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Misc. material regarding MacMillan expeditions, 1924-54 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Navigational Calculations and instructions made by Lawrence Bertram Flint during the 1934 MacMillan arctic expedition (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - "The Evolution of the Sailing Ship" (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - "Nain Kiddies to their Friend, Captain Mac," an album of Inuit children's drawings, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Painting by C. Glaster Pinxit of Lake Bennett (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Three drawings by G. Kleist of Godhavn, Greenland (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Photograph album from Hettasches of Nain, Labrador, 1930; pic. of Moravian school and schoolchildren. (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - MacMillan-Moravian Mission School brochure/appeal for funds, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Posters, Press Releases (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Posters, notices (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Labrador, 1929: Pressed and mounted plant specimens collected by DBM and his team. (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Labrador, 1929: Pressed and mounted plant specimens collected by DBM and his team.
    - Primula mistassinica, michx.; Nain, Labrador; 7/22/29 (Box 7, Envelope 1)
    - Trientalis americana, Pursh.; Nain, Labrador; 7/21/29 (Box 7, Envelope 2)
    - Cornus swecica, L.; Nain, Labrador; 7/23/2029 (Box 7, Envelope 3)
    - Lonicera coerulea, L.; Nain, Labrador; 9/1/2029 (Box 7, Envelope 4)
    - Arnica alpina, L.; Port Manvers, Labrador; 7/26/29 (Box 7, Envelope 5)
    - Statice armeria, L.; Lok Land; 8/12/29 (Box 7, Envelope 6)
    - Draba; Nain, L.; 9/1/29 (Box 7, Envelope 7)
    - Senicio acris, L.; Mugford Island, Labrador; 8/27/29 (Box 7, Envelope 8)
    - Rhianthus oblongifolia, Fernald.; Nain, Labrador; 8/30/29 (Box 7, Envelope 9)
    - Antennaria alpina, L.; Lok Land; 8/12/29 (Box 7, Envelope 10)
    - Pelasites palmata, Ait.; Anetalak, Labrador; 7/12/29 (Box 7, Envelope 11)
    - Euphrasia arctica, Lange.; Mugford Island, Lab.; 8/_/29 (Box 7, Envelope 12)
    - Cardamine praetensis, L.; Baffin Land; 8/20/29 (Box 7, Envelope 13)
    - Arabis alpina, L.; Nachuak, Labrador; 8/2/2029 (Box 7, Envelope 14)
    - Pleurogyna rotata, L.; Nain, Labrador; 8/31/2029 (Box 7, Envelope 15)
    - Tolfieldia palustris, Huds.; Nain, Labrador; 7/22/29 (Box 7, Envelope 16)
    - Listeria cordata, L.; Nain, Labrador; 9/1/2029 (Box 7, Envelope 17)
    - Eriophorum polyptachylon, L.; North Shore, Frobisher's Bay, Baffin Land; 8/20/2029 (Box 7, Envelope 18)
    - Eriophorum vaginatum, L.; North Shore, Frobisher Bay, Baffin Land; 8/21/29 (Box 7, Envelope 19)
    - Saxifraga rivularis, L.; Lok Land; 8/18/2029 (Box 7, Envelope 20)
    - Saxifraga caespitosa, L.; Nachuak, Lab.; 8/3/2029 (Box 7, Envelope 21)
    - Saxifraga cernua, L.; Nachauk, Labrador; 8/2/2029 (Box 7, Envelope 22)
    - Saxifraga aizoon, Jacq.; Nachuak, Labrador; 8/3/39 (Box 7, Envelope 23)
    - Saxifraga azoides; Nain, Labrador; 9/1/29 (Box 7, Envelope 24)
    - Saxifraga tricuspidata, Retz.; Nachuak, Labrador; 8/3/29 (Box 7, Envelope 25)
    - Pinguicula villosa, L.; Nain, Labrador; 7/20/2029 (Box 7, Envelope 26)
    - Linnaea borealis, (var. americana), L.; Nain, Labrador, 9/1/29 (Box 7, Envelope 27)
    - Parnassus katzebuei, c+s; Mugford Island, Labrador; 8/27/29 (Box 7, Envelope 28)
    - Anemone parviflora, michx.; Black Duck Bay, Labrador; 7/28/29 (Box 7, Envelope 29)
    - Ranunculus sp.; North Shore, Frobisher's Bay, Baffin Land; 8/20/29 (Box 7, Envelope 30)
    - Ranunculus pedatifidus; Nachuak, Lab.; 8/2/2029 (Box 7, Envelope 31)
    - Ranunculus pygmaeus, Wald.; Nachuak, Labrador; 8/3/29 (Box 7, Envelope 32)
    - Diapensia lapponicum, L.; Nain, Labrador 7/21/2029 (Box 7, Envelope 33)
    - Campanula rotundiflora, L.; Port Manvers, Labrador; 7/26/29 (Box 7, Envelope 34)
    - Campanula uniflora, L.; Baffin Land; 8/20/2029 (Box 7, Envelope 35)
    - Castilija acuminata/septentrionalis, Spreng.; Mugford Island, Labrador; 8/27/2029 (Box 7, Envelope 36)
    - Pedicularis euphrasoides, steph.; Nain, Labrador; 7/21/29 (Box 7, Envelope 37)
    - Ellephantella graelaudica. Retz.; Mugford Island, Labrador; 8/27/29 (Box 7, Envelope 38)
    - Pedicularis hirsuta, L.; Osbon Bay, Lok Land; 8/9/29 (Box 7, Envelope 39)
    - Pedicularis flammaea, L.; Nain, Labrador; 7/20/2029 (Box 7, Envelope 40)
    - Pedicularis lapponicum, L.; North Shore Frobisher's Bay, Baffin Land; 8/21/29 (Box 7, Envelope 41)
    - Bartsia alpina, L.; Mugford Island, Labrador; 8/27/29 (Box 7, Envelope 42)
    - Viscaria alpina, L.; Mugford Island, Labrador; 8/27/29 (Box 7, Envelope 43)
    - Lychnis apetala, L.; Osbon Bay, Lok Land; 8/9/2029 (Box 7, Envelope 44)
    - Lychnis affinis, vahl.; Baffin Land; 8/20/2029 (Box 7, Envelope 45)
    - Stellaria media, Cyr. (?); Nain, Labrador; 9/1/29 (Box 7, Envelope 46)
    - Equisetum arvense,L.; Osbon Bay, Lok Land; 8/18/29 (Box 7, Envelope 47)
    - Equisetum salvatum, L.; Anetalak, Labrador; 7/18/29 (Box 7, Envelope 48)
    - Crystopteris frigilis (L.) Bernh.; Mugford Island, Labrador; 8/27/29 (Box 7, Envelope 49)
    - Ledum palustre, L.; Anatalak, Labrador; 7/18/2029 (Box 7, Envelope 50)
    - Kalmia polifolia, wang.; Nain, Labrador; 8/31/29. Mugford Island, Labrador; 8/27/2029 (Box 7, Envelope 51)
    - Moneses uniflora, L.; Nain, Labrador; 9/1/2029 (Box 7, Envelope 52)
    - Chamaecistus procumbeus (L.) Kuntze; Lok Land; 8/11/29 (Box 7, Envelope 53)
    - Cassiope hypnoides, L.; Lok Land; 8/11/29 (Box 7, Envelope 54)
    - Oxycoccus oxycoccus,L.; Nain, Labrador; 9/1/2029 (Box 7, Envelope 55)
    - Pyrola minor, L.; Nain, Labrador; 9/1/29 (Box 7, Envelope 56)
    - Vaccinium vitis-idaea (var. minus, Lodd); Anetalak, Labrador; 7/18/29 (Box 7, Envelope 57)
    - Vaccinium uliginosum, L.; Anetalak, Labrador; 7/18/29 (Box 7, Envelope 58)
    - Arctostaphylos uva-ursi, L.; Nain, Labrador; 9/1/29 (Box 7, Envelope 59)
    - Cassiope tetragona, L.; Black Duck Bay, Labrador; 7/28/29 (Box 7, Envelope 60)
    - Phylloduce coerulea, L.; Anetalak, Labrador; 7/18/29 (Box 7, Envelope 61)
    - Veronica alpina, L.; Mugford Island, Labrador; 8/27/29 (Box 7, Envelope 62)
    - Arenaria verna, L.; Nachuak, Labrador; 8/3/2029 (Box 7, Envelope 63)
    - Cerastium alpinum, L.; Nachuak, Labrador; 8/2/2029 (Box 7, Envelope 64)
    - Stellaria longipes, goldie; Mugford Island, Labrador; 8/27/29 (Box 7, Envelope 65)
    - Comarum palustre, L.; Nain, Labrador; 9/1/2029 (Box 7, Envelope 66)
    - Potentilla anserina, L.; Anetalak, Labrador; 7/17/29 (Box 7, Envelope 67)
    - Potentila rubens, Crantz.; Lok Land; 8/12/2029 (Box 7, Envelope 68)
    - Sibbaldia procumbens, L.; Mugford Island, Labrador; 8/27/29 (Box 7, Envelope 69)
    - Onytropis campestris; Nain, Labrador; 9/1/2029 (Box 7, Envelope 70)
    - Chamaenerion latifolium, L.; Nain, Labrador; 9/21/29 (Box 7, Envelope 71)
    - Papaner medicante; Port Manvers, Labrador; 7/20/29 (Box 7, Envelope 72)
    - Erigeron uniflorus, L.; Osbon Bay, Lok Land; 8/18/29 (Box 7, Envelope 73)
    - Solidago multiradiata, Ait.; Mugford Island, Labrador; 8/27/29 (Box 7, Envelope 74)
    - Taraxacum certatophorum, D.C.; Osbon Bay, Lok Land; 8/18/29 (Box 7, Envelope 75)
    - Draba incana; Nain, Labrador; 8/31/29 (Box 7, Envelope 76)
    - Alsine humifessa, Rottb.; a. Frobisher Bay / b. Anetalak, Labrador; 7/17/29 (Box 7, Envelope 77)
    - Mertensia maritima; Anetalak, Labrador; 7/17/2029 (Box 7, Envelope 78)
    - Polyganum viviparum, L.; Osbon Bay, Lok Land; 8/9/29 (Box 7, Envelope 79)
    - Oxyria digyna, L.; Nachuak, Lab.; 8/2/29 (Box 7, Envelope 80)
    - Triglochin maritima, L.; Anetalak, Labrador; 7/17/29 (Box 7, Envelope 81)
    - Honkenya peploides, Ehrh.; Anetalak, Labrador; 7/17/29 (Box 7, Envelope 82)
    - Rubus chamaemorus, L.; Anetalak, Labrador; 7/17/29 (Box 7, Envelope 83)
    - Rubus areticus, L.; Anetalak, Labrador; 7/18/2029 (Box 7, Envelope 84)
  - Posters,notices (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Posters, notices, etc. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Richard Finnie ms (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Botanical notes made by Rutherford B. Platt on the 1947 and 1954 Expeditions (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - MacMillan Open House, 1948 (at Bowdoin) (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - MacMillan Open House, 1949 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - MacMillan Open House, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - MacMillan Open House, 1954 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - MacMillan Open House, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Misc. documents, awards, certificates (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - College rank and attendance reports for DBM, April 6, 1884-April 1, 1898 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Freeport High School report cards for DBM 1891-1893 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Copy of letter of Recommendation for DBM from W. DeWitt Hyde, July 6, 1898 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Levi High School in Gorham, ME: Report cards (DBM principal) for students Lee Plaisted (3/20/1899), Marion Moses (3/20/1899), and Flossie Parker (9/4/1899) (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Misc. documents; awards, certificates (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Documents, certificates, etc (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Documents, certificates, awards (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Awards, certificates, appointment notices (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Misc. documents (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Bradford Washburn Award material (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Misc. printed ephemera (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Misc. news clippings (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Misc. printed material (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - "Labrador's 'Frist Snowmobile' Heads Down the Comback Trail" New York Times, December 12, 2014 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - MacMillan sword (Object Mitchell)
- MacMillan Inuit/English Dictionary, M118.8; 6.65 linear feet
  This series contains notecards for English to Inuit and Inuit to English translations.
  Arranged alphabetically.
  - English to Inuit
    - A-B (Box 9)
    - C-Do (Box 10)
    - Do-F (Box 11)
    - G-H (Box 12)
    - Hou-L (Box 13)
    - M-Pa (Box 14)
    - Pai-R (Box 15)
    - S-Sn (Box 16)
    - Snow-Thus (Box 17)
    - Thus-Window (Box 18)
    - Window-Z (Box 19)
  - Inuit to English
    - A-Arr (Box 19)
    - Arr-It (Box 20)
    - Itiv-Ku (Box 21)
    - Kug-Or (Box 22)
    - Orp-Si (Box 23)
    - Siv-Tu (Box 24)
- Photographs, M118.9; 0.5 linear feet
  This series includes photos of MacMillan at Bowdoin, many images of the schooner "Bowdoin," a few expedition photos, and various photos of MacMillan and others.
  Arranged by size.
  - sm. photos (10) (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - sm. photos (11) (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - sm. photos (9) (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - med. photos (8) (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - med. photos (7) (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - med. photos (9) (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - lg. photos (8) - includes portrait of D. B. MacMillan by Bachrach inscribed for Mary C. Fallon, 1931 Jun 15 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - lg. photos (7) (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - lg. photos (8) (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - lg. photos (9) - includes souvenir photograph of the Bowdoin with vignette insert of D.B. MacMillan, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - lg. photos (10) (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - lg. photos (4) (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - x-lg. photos (3) (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - x-lg. photos (5) (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - x-lg. photos (1) (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - Group photograph - D.B. MacMillan with the Bowdoin track team, 1896 (Ovsz-box Z)
  - Group photograph - D.B. MacMillan with the Bowdoin football team, 1897 (Ovsz-box Z)
  - Group photographs - D.B. MacMillan with the football team at Swarthmore Preparatory School, 1901, 1902, n.d. (Ovsz-box Z)